Halsey V. Barrett Papers
Halsey V. Barrett Papers
1938-1981
Barrett, Halsey V.
6 linear ft.
Papers contain clippings, correspondence, photographs, and political memorabilia from Halsey V. Barrett as well his small film collection. Halsey V. Barrett was co-founder of the American Television Society, an early sales executive for the Columbia Broadcasting System and a key member of the Television Plans Board for the 1952 and 1956 Eisenhower presidential campaigns. Extent of coverage varies.
1650725
Biographical History
Halsey V. Barrett was co-founder of the American Television Society, an early sales executive for the Columbia Broadcasting System and a key member of the Television Plans Board for the 1952 and 1956 Eisenhower presidential campaigns. In the 1980s he was president of Special Situations Ltd., a business brokerage in New York. He served in World War II and is the author of Experiences Aboard the First Ship Sunk In the D-Day Invasion of France.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Halsey V. Barret Papers consists of the personal papers amd memorabilia of the American television executive. Correspondence-subject files includes Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), Federal Communication Commission (FCC), National Broadcasting Corporation (NBC), the Eisenhower TV Plans Board, photographs, mailing lists, clippings, an essay entitled "The Influence of Television on the 1952 Election," and an "I LIKE IKE" official Eisenhower delegate hat. Films are 16mm reels and include episodes of Cavalcade of America, This is Your Music, and others.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection has been only minimally processed and the inventory below is an incomplete box listing.
Related Material
has a number of television-related collections. Please refer to for a complete listing
Subject and Genre Headings
Radio, television, film; Barrett, Halsey V.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; American Television Society.; Columbia Broadcasting System, inc.; Cavalcade of America.; This is your music.; Advertising, political -- United States.; Political campaigns.; Television broadcasting -- United States.; Television in politics -- United States.; 16mm (photographic film size); Articles.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographic film (photographic materials); Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Halsey V. Barrett.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Correspondence, 1947; 1951-1953,; 1955-1956,; 1958-1959,; 1981 (Box 1)
  - American Television Society (Box 1)
  - Color TV (Box 1)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS), 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (CBS) (cont.) (Box 2)
  - Daytime TV (Box 2)
  - DuMont (Box 2)
  - Dunla (?), Orrine (Box 2)
  - FCC 8736, 8975, 8976, 9175, 1949 (Box 2)
  - FCC 6780 / Promulgation of Rules and Regulations, 1945 (Box 2)
  - FCC 7896 / Hearings, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - General Television Committee for Pooled Coverage of Republican and Democratic National Conventions, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Gould, Jack (Box 2)
    See also New York Times.
  - Marketing (Box 3)
  - NARTB [National Association of Radio and Television Broadcasters] (Box 3)
  - National Association of Radio Station Representatives (Box 3)
  - National Broadcasting System (NBC) (Box 3)
    See also Sarnoff, David.
  - New York Times (Box 3)
    See also Gould, Jack.
  - R.C.A. (Box 3)
  - Sarnoff, David (Box 3)
    See also NBC.
  - Satellite TV (Box 3)
  - Satellite TV, issue of New York Times, on topic (Oversize 3)
  - Society of Motion Picture Engineers, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Television Broadcasting Association (Box 3)
  - Television Bureau of Advertising, Inc. (Box 3)
  - United States Television Manufacturing Corporation (Box 3)
- Memorabilia
  - "Agenda" Jack Denove Productions (Box 3)
  - American Research Bureau (Box 3)
  - Barrett, Halsey V., clippings about (Box 2)
    See also Scrapbook pages, below.
  - CBS Color TV, clippings about (Box 3)
  - Certificate of appreciation (Box 3)
  - Dinner invitations (Box 3)
  - Eisenhower
    - Campaign hat, "I LIKE IKE" (Oversize 1)
    - TV Plans Board
      - Confidential memos, 1951-1952; 1960 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - The Influence of Television on the 1952 Election (Box 3)
  - List of potential TV speakers (Box 3)
  - Mailing lists (Box 3)
  - Map, "Television Stations Across the United States," from 1951-52 Broadcasting article, January 28, 1952 (Box 3)
  - "New Directions for Television," Television Talk (Box 4)
  - Photographs (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1938-1942; 1944-1946; many with clippings; 10 folders (Oversize 2)
  - Scrapbook pages, 1947-1952; 1956; many with clippings; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Telecast, November 1969 (Box 4)
  - Television Broadcasters Association, 2nd Television Conference, New York, October 10-11, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Television Planning in the 1952 Eisenhower Campaign (Box 4)
  - "Television Talk," NBC Television, 1946; glossary of televion engineering and production terms (Box 4)
  - Witting, Chris J., 1949; clippings (Box 4)
  - World Series, [1947?]; photographs (Box 4)
- Writings
  - Articles by Barrett (Box 4)
- Films
  - Film ephemera, paper items associated with barrett_hv_020 and barrett_hv_003 (Box 4)
  - Cavalcade of America
    - Crazy Judah (Cavalcade of America series) 3900, barrett_hv_010; Film: 16mm
    - The Hostage (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_001; Film: 16mm
    - A Man's Home Part 1 (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_011; Film: 16mm
    - Margin for Victory, 10 Jan 1957; barrett_hv_020; associated ephemera (two-page packet) housed in a folder in Box 4; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - The Marine Who Was 200 Years Old (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_012; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - The Marine Who Was 200 Years Old (Print #1) (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_013; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - The Marine Who Was 200 Years Old (Print #6) (Cavalcade of America series), 4 Jan 1955; 10 Jan 1957; barrett_hv_014; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - Night Call (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_015; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - Night Call (Print #9) (Cavalcade of America series), Dec. 8, 1954; barrett_hv_016; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - The Ship That Shook the World (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_002; Film: 16mm
    - Take Off Zero (Cavalcade of America series), barrett_hv_017; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - That They May Live (Print #1) (Cavalcade of America series), Jack Denove Prod., barrett_hv_003; associated ephemera (two-page packet) housed in a folder in Box 4.; Film: 16mm
    - Young Andy Jackson (Cavalcade of America series), Jack Denove Prod., Jan 1957; barrett_hv_004; includes a two-page packet entitled, "The Jack Denove Story: STORYBOARD TO CELLULOID -- The Way You Want It; 'A guy who has been through the advertising mill and who has then mastered film techniques, is an unbeatable combination.'"; Film: 16mm
  - The Christophers: A Link in the Chain C3387, barrett_hv_021; Film: 16mm, b/w
  - Modern Romances, 10/12/1956; barrett_hv_022; Film: 16mm, b/w
  - Smyrna Incident (U.S. Navy) 3210-1, barrett_hv_018; Film: 16mm, b/w
  - Steve Donovan, Texas Ranger, barrett_hv_019; Film: 16mm, b/w
  - This is Your Music
    - Academy Awards Pt. #4 (This is Your Music series), Jan Prod. 5000-3, barrett_hv_005; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - Academy Awards Pt. #15 (This is Your Music series), Jan Prod. 5000-3, barrett_hv_006; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - Academy Awards Pt. #18 (This is Your Music series), Jan Prod. 5000-3, barrett_hv_007; includes folded 8.5 x 11” sheet of paper with printed or photocopied article from The Billboard Television Review about "This Is Your Music (TV Film)," with a highlighted quote, "...probably the best musical show ever done either live or on film for television"; Film: 16mm, b/w
    - Latin American Show - Pt. #12 (This is Your Music series), Jan Prod. 5000-6, barrett_hv_008; Film: 16mm
    - Gay Nineties (Print #6) (This is Your Music series), Jan Prod. 5000-4, barrett_hv_009; Film: 16mm